Phyllis McGinley Papers
Phyllis McGinley Papers
- Writings
  - Essays
    - "Profession: Housewife"
      - "Profession: Housewife: White Gloves and Ritual Curtsies" - Ladies' Home Journal, Sept. 1963 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Why Educate Women?" - Ladies' Home Journal, 1962 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Why It's Important to Teach Good Manners" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 20, 1965 (Box 41)
      - "Profession: Housewife: Worthiness of a Domestic Career" - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, Jan. 22, 1965 (Box 41)
    - "Recommended Summer Reading", ms. drafts (Box 41)
    - "The Quality of Mercy", ms. drafts (2 folders); ms., copyedited (Box 41)
    - "The Realms of Gilt", ms. draft, manuscript (Box 41)
    - "Recipe for a Successful Summer" - Glamour, May 1952 (Box 41)
    - "Reproachful Ghosts" - America, Mar. 25, 1961 (Box 41)
    - "The Saints of Ireland", ms. drafts (Box 41)
    - "Saint-Watching", ms. drafts (Box 41)
    - "The Sentimental Trap" (working title: "Groundhog Day Is a Holiday"), ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 41)
    - "The Sentimentalists", manuscript; production records - galley proofs (Box 41)
    - "The Servant in the House", ms. drafts, manuscript (Box 41)
    - "Shopping Postscripts" - The New York Post, Aug. 10, 1934 (Box 41)
    - "Should You Tell Your Daughter Unchastity Is a Sin?" - New York Journal-American, June 10, 1956 (Box 41)
    - "Some People Collect Butterflies, But Most Write Poetry" - The New York Times Book Review, Aug. 20, 1950 (Box 41)
    - "Speaking of Books" - The New York Times Book Review (Box 41)
    - "Suburbia: of Thee I Sing" - Harper's Magazine, Dec. 1949 (Box 41)
    - "Talking Down" - Glamour, Sept. 1960; Wilson Library Bulletin, Apr. 1962 (Box 41)
    - "10 Ways to Keep a Husband--Young" (working title: "How Not to Kill Your Husband"), work sheets (Box 41)
    - "10 Ways to Keep a Husband--Young" (working title: "Eleven Ways to Keep a Husband--Alive"), manuscript (Box 41)
    - "10 Ways to Keep a Husband--Young" - Ladies' Home Journal, winter 1963 (Box 41)
    - "The Third Hand" - The Key of Kappa Kappa Gamma, Feb. 1954 (Box 41)
    - "Three Against the Grain", ms. Drafts, manuscript (Box 42)
    - "The Three Hundred Sixty Five Days of Christmas", ms. drafts (Box 42)
    - "Tribute to an Honored Guest" - The Harvard Advocate, vol. CVII, no. 2/3 (Box 42)
    - "The Trouble with Christmas", production records - galley proofs (Box 42)
    - "The Trouble with Christmas" - The American Weekly, Nov. 30, 1958 (Box 42)
    - "A Vote for Suburbia" - The New York Times Magazine, Feb. 14, 1954 (Box 42)
    - "What Every Bride Should Know", manuscript (Box 42)
    - "What Every (Mother of the) Bride Should Know", ms. Drafts, manuscript (Box 42)
    - "What Every (Mother of the) Bride Should Know" - Ladies' Home Journal, June 1965 (Box 42)
    - "What Is a Saint?", ms. drafts, manuscript, manuscript - "last version" (Box 42)
    - "What Is a Saint?" - The Critic, June/July 1968 (Box 42)
    - "What Leisure? a Suburban Report", manuscript (Box 42)
    - "What Makes a Children's 'Classic'?", manuscript (Box 42)
    - "What Makes a Children's 'Classic'?" - The Griffin, Oct. 1959 (Box 42)
    - "What Shall I Tell My Daughters?", manuscript (Box 42)
    - "What Shall I Tell My Daughters?" - The Reader's Digest, Nov. 1959 (Box 42)
    - "What the Saint Told the Sinner" (working title: "The Road to Self-Respect"), manuscript (Box 42)
    - "What the Saint Told the Sinner" - This Week Magazine, May 22, 1960 (Box 42)
    - "What to Take Along on a Weekend", manuscript (Box 42)
    - "Why We Teach" (for Famous Writers School), ms. drafts (Box 42)
    - "The Wine of the Country", work sheets (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - "The Wit of Saints" (working title: "Holy Wit"), ms. Drafts, manuscript (Box 42)
    - "The Wit of Saints" - Vogue, Apr. 1962 (Box 42)
    - "Woman's Place Is ...?", transcript of dialogue (Box 42)
    - "Woman's Place Is ...?" - The Sign, July 1965 (Box 42)
    - "Women Are Better Drivers" (working title: "Ladies on the Highway"), manuscript (Box 42)
    - "Women Are Better Drivers" - The American Weekly, Jan. 11, 1959; Catholic Digest, May 1959 (Box 42)
    - "Women Are Wonderful" - Life, Dec. 24, 1956 (Box 42)
    - "Young Readers Call Them 'Keen" - The New York Times Book Review, Dec. 24, 1950 (Box 42)
    - Untitled - "My very dear Sybil ..." (Box 42)
    - Untitled - "Once, many years ago when I was young and naive ..." (Box 42)
    - Untitled fragments (various) (Box 42)
    - Work sheets (various) (Box 42)
  - Interviews
    - "Camp Fire Salute to the Stars", 1942 (Box 42)
    - Donald McDonald interviews Phyllis McGinley, 1960 (Box 42)
    - Ilka Chase interviews Phyllis McGinley, 1942 (Box 42)
    - "Mary Margaret McBride Interviews Phyllis McGinley", 1948 (Box 42)
    - "Viewpoint" - taped interview, 1964 (Box 43)
    - "Woman's Page of the Air" - Adelaide Hawley interviews Phyllis McGinley, 1938; 1941 (Box 43)
  - Lyrics
    - "The Banana Man", printed material (Box 43)
    - "Birthday Song" (Box 43)
    - "Come Blow Your Horn", 5 folders (Box 43)
    - "Garden Magic" (Box 43)
      transferred to Rare Book collections
    - "Hallowe'en Song" (Box 43)
    - "The Humming Top" (Box 43)
    - "The Lady Says Yes" (Box 43)
    - "The Legend of Befana", printed material (Box 43)
    - Music: Highways and Byways, c1936; contributions by Phyllis McGinley (Box 43)
    - "Personal and Private Song Cycles" / Elizabeth Gould and Phyllis McGinley (Oversize 1)
    - "The Plains of Uruguay", printed material (Box 43)
    - "Renting the Hive" (Box 43)
    - "Sitting Home" (Box 43)
    - "Small Wonder", includes printed material (Box 43)
    - "The Street of Little Houses", printed material (Box 43)
    - "The Toy Shop", printed material (Box 43)
    - "Walk the Plank!" (Box 43)
    - "The Wandering Babushka" (Box 43)
  - Poetry
    - "Early Poems", 3 folders (Box 44)
    - A-Gh (by title), 14 fol ers (Box 44)
    - Gi-So (by title), 18 folders (Box 45)
    - Sp-Z (by title), 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Untitled poems, manuscript (Box 46)
    - Untitled fragment, manuscript (Box 46)
    - "The Inconsistencies of Philosophy" (collection) (Box 46)
    - "The Make-Believe Twins" (collection) - Ladies' Home Journal (Box 46)
    - Untitled collection - "Class at Columbia University 1932" (Box 46)
    - Untitled collection, production records - galley proofs (Box 46)
    - Book "presentation copy", note samples printed material (Box 46)
    - Commercial, advertisements, commissions (Box 46)
    - Work sheets, 4 folders (Box 46)
    - Workbooks (Box 46)
    - Workbooks (Box 47)
    - Indexes (Box 47)
  - Reviews
    - A-Z (by title), 1 folder (Box 47)
  - Scripts
    - "Alice in Leonardland" (Box 47)
    - "Mary's Garden" (Box 47)
    - "Mr. Christopher", fragment (Box 47)
    - Untitled play, manuscript (Box 47)
  - Speeches
    - Atlanta Book Fair, 1948 (Box 47)
    - Campion Award, 1967 (Box 47)
    - Catholic Book Club Annual Dinner, 1959 (Box 47)
    - Catholic Poetry Society of America, 1962 (Box 47)
    - Cosmopolitan Club, 1954 (Box 47)
    - Kappa Kappa Gamma, 1952 (Box 47)
    - Larchmont Book and Author Luncheon, 1960 (Box 47)
    - Lippincott Night, 1952 (Box 47)
    - Richmond, Virgin a, Book and Author Dinner, 1956 (Box 47)
    - Theta Phi Alpha Siena Medal Award Presentation, 1956 (Box 47)
    - Unidentified occasion (Box 47)
    - Unidentified occasion, introductory remarks for reading from A Short Walk from the Station (Box 47)
  - Stories
    - "The Belle-Maker", manuscript (Box 47)
    - "Dinner with the Family", manuscript (Box 47)
    - "First Communion", manuscript (Box 47)
    - "Hail", manuscript (Box 47)
    - "The Horse Who Had His Picture in the Paper" (with suggested Houghton Mifflin changes) (Box 47)
    - "The Horse Who Lived Upstairs" - My Weekly Reader C, 1969 (Box 47)
    - "The Jacket" - Cosmopolitan Jan. 1945 (Box 47)
    - "Old Mill", manuscript (Box 47)
    - "The Plain Princess", page proofs, for The Readers' Digest anthology (Box 47)
    - Untitled, ms. drafts (Box 47)
    - Untitled fragments, manuscript (Box 47)
  - Miscellany
    - "Alma Kitchell's Streamline Journal", transcript (Box 47)
    - "Born on Saturday" (autobiographical), notes (Box 47)
    - Commercial, advertisements, commissions (Box 47)
    - "The Emperor's Nightingale", narrative adaptation of Hans Christian Andersen (Box 47)
    - Form letter drafts; invitation refusals (Box 47)
    - Form letter drafts - "Oliver Ames" (Box 47)
    - Journal, 1949-1951; undated; 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Juvenilia, manuscript (6 folders) (Box 48)
    - "Mr. Perkins" (fragment), unpublished book ms. (children's novel); work sheets, ms. drafts (2 folders) (Box 48)
    - Notes (miscellaneous) (Box 48)
    - "Notes on Saint Madelein Sophie as an Educator" (Box 48)
    - "Outline for a Possible 'American' Article" (working title: "Exit: the Villain") (Box 48)
    - Prefaces
      - Casserole Cookery Complete, ms. Drafts, manuscript (Box 48)
      - The Decline of Pleasure / Walter Kerr, ms. draft (not used), manuscript (not used) (Box 48)
      - Dwarf Long-Nose / Wilhelm Hauff, manuscript (Box 48)
      - A Little Princess / Frances Hodgson Burnett, manuscript (Box 48)
      - Never Underestimate the Power of a Woman, manuscript (Box 48)
      - Poems for Partly Proud Parents / Richard Armour, manuscript (Box 48)
      - The Screwtape Letters / Clive Staples Lewis (working title: "In Praise of Sin: a Preface to The Screwtape Letters"), 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Unidentified (Box 48)
    - Quotations, printed material; 2 folders (Box 49)
    - Reading for Library of Congress recording, manuscript (Box 49)
    - Response to Marion K. Sanders' article "A Proposition for Women", manuscript (Box 49)
    - "The Show-Off Poodle", ms. draft (Box 49)
    - Unidentified project (Box 49)
    - Workbook (Box 49)
- Memorabilia
  - Academic robes (Oversize 4)
  - Calendars, 1953-1961 (Oversize 3)
  - Card file of saints (Box 49)
  - Card file of saints, cont. (Box 50)
  - Crossword puzzles completed by McGinley and containing her name in the clues (Box 50)
  - Diploma - B. A., University of Utah (Box 50)
  - Financial
    - Account books, 1951-1953; 1958-1963,; 1963-1969; 3 volumes (Box 50)
    - Bank check records (Box 50)
    - Bank check records (Box 51)
    - Bank check records (Box 52)
    - Bank check records (Box 53)
    - Bank check records (Box 54)
    - Bank check records (Box 55)
    - Bank check records (Box 56)
    - Lists and graphs of book royalties (Box 56)
    - Permissions, 1944-1974; 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Receipts (Curtis Brown, Ltd.) (Box 56)
    - Receipts (miscellaneous) (Box 57)
    - Receipts and expenses - disposition of property (Box 57)
    - Royalty statements
      - Anchorage Press (Box 57)
      - [C. C.] Birchard & Co. (Box 57)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation (Box 57)
      - Brockhampton Press (Box 57)
      - Caedmon Records (Box 57)
      - Chappell & Co., Inc. (Box 57)
      - Children's Theatre Press (Box 57)
      - Collier Books (Box 57)
      - [J. M.] Dent & Sons Ltd. (Box 57)
      - The Dramatists' Guild, Inc. (Box 57)
      - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc. (Box 57)
      - Ginn and Company (Box 57)
      - Hallmark Cards, Inc. (Box 57)
      - Hawthorn Books (Box 57)
      - [J. B.] Lippincott Company, 1944-1974; 6 folders (Box 57)
      - Macmillan Company Meredith Press (Box 58)
      - [G.] Schirmer, Inc. (Box 58)
      - Secker & Warburg Ltd. Shawnee Press Inc. (Box 58)
      - Viking Press Inc., 1946-1975; 4 folders (Box 58)
      - [Franklin] Watts, Inc. (Box 58)
      - World's Work Ltd. (Box 58)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 58)
    - Tax calculations and records, 1953-1958; 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Tax calculations and records, 1959-1960; 1965; 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Miscellany (Box 59)
  - Legal
    - Contracts, The New Yorker, 1943-1970; 1973 (Box 59)
    - Contracts, miscellaneous, 1928-1974; undated; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Copyright certificates, transfers and renewals (Box 59)
    - Lawsuit, "Hayden vs. Chapman Park Hotel" (Box 59)
    - Leases (Box 59)
  - Lists (Box 59)
  - Photographs (Box 59)
  - Photographs (Box 60)
  - Plaque, "What the Saint Told the Sinner" (Box 60)
  - Portrait (Box 60)
  - Printed material
    - Articles about, general, 1920-1969; undated; 6 folders (Box 60)
    - Articles about, awards (Box 60)
    - Articles about, peripheral mentions, 5 folders (Box 61)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous (Box 61)
    - Postcards, occasional cards (blank) (Box 61)
    - Programs (Box 61)
    - Publicity
      - Books (by title) (Box 61)
      - Books (by title) (Box 62)
      - Books (multiple titles) (Box 62)
      - Miscellany (TV, radio appearances, etc.) (Box 62)
    - Reviews
      - All Around the Town (Box 62)
      - Blunderbus (Box 62)
      - Boys Are Awful (Box 62)
      - Christmas Legends (Box 62)
      - "The Emperor's Nightingale" (Box 62)
      - A Girl and Her Room (Box 62)
      - The Horse Who Had His Picture in the Paper (Box 62)
      - The Horse Who Lived Upstairs (Box 62)
      - How Mrs. Santa Claus Saved Christmas (Box 62)
      - Husbands Are Difficult (Box 62)
      - The Love Letters of Phyllis McGinley (Box 62)
      - Lucy McLockett (Box 62)
      - The Make-Believe Twins (Box 63)
      - Merry Christmas, Happy New Year (Box 63)
      - Mince Pie and Mistletoe (Box 63)
      - The Most Wonderful Doll in the World (Box 63)
      - On the Contrary (Box 63)
      - One More Manhattan (Box 63)
      - The Plain Princess (Box 63)
      - A Pocketful of Wry (Box 63)
      - The Province of the Heart (Box 63)
      - Saint-Watching (Box 63)
      - A Short Walk from the Station (Box 63)
      - Sixpence in Her Shoe (Box 63)
      - Stones from a Glass House (Box 63)
      - Sugar and Spice: the ABC of Being a Girl (Box 63)
      - Times Three (Box 63)
      - Wonders and Surprises (Box 63)
      - A Wreath of Christmas Legends (Box 63)
      - The Year Without a Santa Claus (Box 63)
    - School publications
      - High Lights - Albert Leonard Junior High School, 1931; 1934 (Box 63)
      - The University Pen, 1924-1925 (Box 63)
      - Yearbooks
        - O. H. S. The Classicum, 1920 (Box 64)
        - Utonian, 1925 (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 64)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 64)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 65)
  - Scrapbook (oversize) (Oversize 2)
  - Scrapbook (partial) (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 65)